Hi everybody. I'm John Kiriakou and this
is the briefing room. Before we start
with today's news and there's a lot of
news, I want to thank you
deeply. We've been doing this show for 2
weeks and last night we crossed 200,000
subscribers. So thank you. Thank you.
Thank you. Please continue to like, to
subscribe, to watch, to tell your
friends and family members and please go
ahead and comment. We're taking in all
of these comments and there have been so
many fantastic ideas whether whether
technical or ideas for for future
episodes, we're considering everything.
So please keep it up. Maybe we'll do
something on famous assassinations or or
whatever. We're looking at all of these
ideas. So thank you very much.
As I said, we have a lot of news to get
to today. I want to say hi from Miami,
Florida today.
I'm doing some other recording here, but
most importantly, last night Iran
launched another round of missiles at a
US base in Jordan after a very brief
pause in strikes. Now,
that came after US and Saudi forces
attacked Iranian or pro-Iranian militias
in Iraq. Now, I'm going to blow my horn
here. Didn't we say a week ago we were
looking at expansion of this conflict
and it was going to turn into a regional
war? Well, now it's not just the US and
Israel against Iran. The Iranians of
course have been bombing Saudi Arabia,
Kuwait, Bahrain, Qatar,
Oman, the United Arab Emirates, Jordan.
Well, now the Saudis are involved and
remember a few days ago Yemen's Houthis
got involved and said that they would
begin attacking Saudi ships. They've
done that. Not just Saudi ships, but
Saudi oil
And now the Saudis are striking back,
not just against the Houthis, but
against pro-Iranian militias in Iraq.
It's a regional war. Whether we've
called that called it that officially or
not, it's a regional war.
We've also got another bombshell video
of Lindsey Graham
talking strategy with Benjamin
Netanyahu.
And a shocking new poll showing that a
majority, not a plurality, a majority
of Americans support the arrest of
Benjamin Netanyahu. That is
significantly higher, that number.
Significantly higher than the share of
Americans who supported the arrest of
Nicholas Maduro. And according to CNN,
it represents a 50%
point move just over the last 5 years.
But I want to start by showing you some
footage from yesterday at Lindsey
Graham's funeral.
I think you're going to enjoy this. Some
of these exchanges you see here
Benjamin Netanyahu on the left,
President Zelensky of Ukraine on the
right. He's speaking to Secretary of
State Marco Rubio in the center. And
then later on you see Pete Hegseth, the
Secretary of Defense walk in and Scott
Bessent, the Secretary of the Treasury
walks in.
Um
it's it wasn't just a funeral. It was a
meeting of the minds. Some of these
exchanges, the body language tells you a
lot. It was a real who's who of what
we're going to call maximus maximalist
US foreign policy. Zelensky was making
the rounds with Netanyahu. What do they
have in common? They both want more and
more and more American missiles.
Then you had Netanyahu standing there
and this is kind of dramatic. If you
look, he ends up wagging his finger at
Marco Rubio and Pete Hegseth.
You almost have to admire that in kind
of a funny way. Here's Here's the
Israeli Prime Minister, a wildly
unpopular one,
at that, on camera,
appearing to lecture the American
Secretaries of State and Defense.
No doubt enjoying being on video giving
orders to Pete Hegseth.
So, here you can see Rubio does this
little spin to look away as Netanyahu's
talking.
Everything is done for a reason at these
levels.
It's tough, of course, for us to know
what they're talking about. There was no
audio that was associated with but maybe
deploying ground troops? I mean, that's
kind of the logical next next topic of
conversation. Maybe Iran's latest
missile attack on Jordan? Whatever.
Whatever it was, Netanyahu certainly
looked like the one doing most of the
talking. And then, after the funeral was
over,
Prime Minister Netanyahu went to the
White House and had a closed-door
meeting with President Trump. Once that
meeting was done,
he then gave an exclusive interview to
Sean Hannity. We're going to talk about
that in a second. So, after the funeral,
Netanyahu left to go to the White House
for this closed press meeting at the
Oval Office, meaning no reporters were
allowed to attend.
No reporters.
So, I want you to ask yourself,
why do you think no reporters were
allowed to attend?
We're We're talking about two major
world leaders who love love love to get
in front of cameras.
So, why were two of the most
camera-happy leaders in the world
afraid to answer questions?
I think it's because the reality is
the relationship between Donald Trump
Benjamin Netanyahu has never been any
more tense.
Listen to this quote from Netanyahu on
the meeting and tell me if you think
this sounds legit.
>> Um, I don't think the world's seen
anything like it.
And, you know,
you met with the president today.
>> Yeah.
>> How'd that meeting go?
>> It was great.
It was one
one of the best meetings that we've had.
And I always,
you know, I always hate to disappoint uh
our would-be critics
uh who are trying to find, you know,
cracks in our alliance. And what they
find, like today,
is a wall of granite,
cuz the president is so clear. I mean,
he's so We have a common commitment. We
don't want to see this
fanatic regime in Tehran have nuclear
weapons to threaten
every American
uh and to threaten the peace of the
world and to threaten the existence of
Israel. So, we have a common goal. And
it's going to be achieved either through
diplomatic means or other means.
>> It's a wall of granite.
The US-Israeli relationship is a wall of
granite.
But it's not, at least not according to
Donald Trump. The president went on
Fox & Friends the next morning. He He
called in, which he frequently does.
And uh
and they asked him about the meeting
with Netanyahu. Check out what he said
then.
>> Iran will not have a nuclear weapon.
There are reports now that um Netanyahu
is going to talk to you about ongoing
excavation at um Pickaxe Mountain,
construction vehicles entering and
exiting exiting tunnels, paving new
access roads, satellite imagery and
intel indicates that Iran is actively
constructing and fortifying Pickaxe
Mountain. How will we respond?
>> Well, I don't need Bibi to tell me that.
Bibi's telling me that cuz he wants me
to stay involved. I mean, I don't
necessarily We have
the finest because of space force. We
have the greatest cameras in the world
focused. So, we know exactly what's
going on.
But, uh no, I heard Bibi announce that.
I said, "Why don't you just tell it to
me? Why do you have to announce it to
the world? I know exactly what's going
on at Pickax. It's not a big problem. We
took out their nuclear sites, and we'll
have to take out Pickax if we don't make
a deal. We don't make a deal, we'll take
it out very easily.
>> Listen, everything that Donald Trump
said there in that clip
is true. Everything he said is true. So,
let's break it down.
Benjamin Benjamin Netanyahu is is a
consummate uh politician. He's
constantly working on public opinion.
And he knows that American public
opinion, at least on Israel and on
Muslim countries, is is easily
malleable.
Right? All you have to do is say,
"Islam, terrorism, nuclear." And
everybody just runs around like their
hair is on fire.
Um
Donald Trump does what he's doing
because Trump is a master of the media.
Donald Trump is terrific at manipulating
the media. He always has been. I can
tell you when when he used to have his
show, The Apprentice,
I used to lay in bed with my then wife
and watch the show, and I remember
turning to her and saying, "You know,
I've got to admit, Trump has won me
over. I feel like I'm halfway through an
MBA just watching this show."
He's great at using the media.
So, he's right when he says, "Why does
Bibi have to say this to the public?"
about Pickax Mountain, and we're going
to bomb them again, and we're going to
bomb them into submission, and they're a
an existential threat to the United
States as well as to Israel. Why say all
that?
Because you're trying to influence
American public opinion
to pressure the president to do what you
want him to do.
And I think Trump is tired of it.
He's tired of Netanyahu constantly
trying to manipulate him.
And I want to make another point, too.
And
this is going to maybe be a little
controversial.
But
we've all seen video of Netanyahu
speaking before Congress
in 2002
and saying, "Saddam Hussein is an
existential threat to Israel and to the
United States. If we overthrow Saddam
Hussein, there will be peace in the
Middle East." And then there wasn't.
And then he's testifying before Congress
in 2008 or 2009 and he says, "If we
overthrow Muammar Gaddafi and the Libyan
government, they're an existential
threat to the United States and to
Israel. We'll have peace in the Middle
East." And we did that, and it just made
everything worse.
And then a year ago, he's before
Congress saying, "If we overthrow the
Iranian government, they're an
existential threat to the United States
and to and to Israel, and we'll have
peace in the Middle East." No,
we won't. We do all of Israel's dirty
work for it.
We kill thousands, tens of thousands of
people, and what do we get out of it?
Nothing. Well, I'll tell you what I
think
is a little bit controversial. If you
are the leader of Iran or a leader of
Iran,
what do you do to protect yourself?
The only thing that you can do
is build a nuclear weapon.
We are not having a conversation right
now, for example, about North Korea. You
know why? Because North Korea has a
nuclear weapon.
And so nobody dares attack North Korea.
Well, if you're Iranian, the only thing
you can do to protect yourself from from
this ongoing war or any future war is to
develop a nuclear weapon.
And I think, frankly, that's the next
step. You can't bomb them forever.
So, anyway, in this Trump quote, it's
the president of the United States
telling
an ally, the country's closest ally,
maybe, "You better not say anything to
the press first without running it by
me."
in public
on a cable news hit. And let me add one
other thing. There was something else
that the president and Netanyahu spoke
about yesterday. And that was the
possible sale of F-35 fighter jets to
Turkey. Now, the Greek government and
Greek-Americans have long been opposed
to the sale of F-35s to Turkey because,
frankly,
we're afraid the Turks are going to use
them against Greece. Well,
the Israelis are afraid the Turks are
going to use them against Israel.
And so, Netanyahu has been strongly
opposed to the sale of F-35s to Turkey.
He mentioned that in public yesterday,
and the president didn't appreciate it.
And he said, "I don't take my orders
from a foreign leader
as to
which country I can make sales
military sales to."
And he meant it.
It was a slap-down
to Bibi Netanyahu, something that we
hadn't we hadn't yet seen. And I'll let
you in on another little secret.
Presidents get caught off guard by news
all the time.
Even about what their allies are doing
or have claimed they would do. They
really do not like hearing news from
reporters before getting it from the
mouth of the foreign leader. When that
happens, presidents usually fall back on
diplomatic stock phrases, things like
I don't discuss private conversations
with foreign leaders.
Or we're in constant communication. The
situation is evolving.
Or any one of the other hundred thousand
phrases in the lexicon of national
security silliness and and international
diplomacy, which is why it is such a big
deal that Trump chose to reprimand
Netanyahu for discussing strategy with
reporters rather than just
BS the question.
You don't have to answer every question
a reporter throws at you.
Especially when you know or ought to
know that your answer is going to anger
the president of the United States.
But Bibi right now is a very happy man
that he got this meeting at all. And
listen to this statement from
Netanyahu's communications director
about their relationship with Trump.
Here's what he said, quote, "There is no
truth in the claim that Israel is
pushing the US in a certain direction on
the Iran issue. The Prime Minister is
not telling the US president what to do
and is not pushing him in any
direction."
You have to be utterly brain dead
to believe a single word of that. It's
actually offensive as an American
and as somebody who, you know,
watches the news even a little bit, it's
offensive
that the Israeli Prime Minister's
communications director think any
American would believe that.
Does that sound like something
you would say if you were not pushing
your friend in a certain direction?
Would you deny it multiple times in a
few sentences?
Well, after that little show from
Netanyahu, Trump told Fox News this
morning,
"Excellent meeting," he said. "Bibi
understands now."
So, apparently it was enough. BB
understands now. That tells me that the
president slapped him down.
What if the way money works is about to
change? Not someday, not hypothetically,
but right now.
China and the United States are both
making moves that suggest we could be
heading towards something the world
hasn't seen in more than 50 years. A
return to gold-backed money or something
very close to it. China is shutting down
paper gold trading at four of its
biggest banks, all on the same day.
And they're building a new system that
settles in physical gold instead. On our
side, the government is sitting on more
than 8,000 tons of gold still valued at
$42 an ounce on the books. Legislation
to fix that is already in Congress. If
both superpowers start anchoring their
currencies to gold, what happens to the
price? And more importantly, what
happens to every dollar in your
retirement that isn't backed by anything
at all?
That's the question a free report from
American Alternative Assets answers.
It's called The Day Money Changes
Forever. And if you have an IRA or a
401k, you need to read it right now. Get
your free copy at johnlovesgold.com.
That's johnlovesgold.com
or call 888-GOLD-053.
Well, I started this episode by saying
that there was a lot of news to get
through, and there is a lot of news. We
just didn't think yesterday when we
started putting this together that so
much of it would be focused on Israel,
but here we are. Let's talk about
Netanyahu and the International Criminal
Court. I want to show you something else
that's disturbing. We have given Lindsey
Graham a lot of airtime on the show the
last 2 weeks, but I truly cannot think
of a more revealing person
as far as how Benjamin Netanyahu
captured US officials and anyone
sympathetic to his cause. Last night
we got some crocodile tears from
Netanyahu about how difficult the
International Criminal Court is
potentially making his life.
After all, he's been charged with war
crimes and crimes against humanity.
Let's listen to what Sean Hannity had to
say.
>> But it scares me in this sense for you.
Um
you travel internationally.
>> Yep.
>> God forbid you had a medical emergency
and you need to land.
And you're you're about to land in a
country that recognizes the ICC. It
could complicate things. Do you worry
about that?
>> Yeah, I think about it. You know, we
have we have
special forces around, you know, I
served in the for 5 years.
>> Well, the idea of it's pretty tough.
They have a very tough job.
>> give them a new task, you know. Yeah, of
course it's Look, it's the corruption of
the international system. It's an
unelected unelected bureaucracy that
sits in The Hague that it could arrest
American soldiers because you don't
recognize this corrupt body any more
than we do. And they could say that the
president of the United States is a war
criminal.
That American soldiers valiantly
fighting next to us shoulder to shoulder
against these the tyranny in Tehran,
that they're war criminals. They could
pick them up.
>> Man, there's so much to talk about here.
The United States and Israel are not
signatories to what's called the Rome
Statute. The Rome Statute created the
ICC and made it something akin to what
we had at Nuremberg after the Second
World War where Nazi war criminals were
given a fair trial. Some were acquitted
and others were convicted, some were
executed, some were imprisoned. But
there ought to be an international
agreement that when somebody commits war
crimes or somebody commits crimes
against humanity, that they're dealt
with.
Right? Look at Slobodan Milosevic, the
former dictator of Yugoslavia. He died
in a prison cell in The Hague.
As he should have.
But the United States doesn't recognize
the ICC and Israel doesn't recognize the
ICC. And so Netanyahu is free to come
and go from the United States as he
pleases. And he comes many times a year.
But what happens if he has a medical
emergency on a flight? What happens if
the plane has engine trouble and it's
forced to land in
Italy,
Austria, Greece, Spain,
wherever, Ireland.
The leaders of those countries are
compelled by treaty
to arrest him and to turn him over to
the ICC. Okay, what would happen in in
that event?
Well, Congress has already thought about
what would happen.
During the Obama administration,
Congress passed something known as the
Hague Invasion Act,
which authorizes the president
to call out the US military to invade
the Netherlands.
To invade the Netherlands
and to take over
the International Criminal Court to then
free Benjamin Netanyahu and let him run
back to Israel.
This is how crazy the world has gotten.
Now, when Netanyahu talks about
unelected bureaucrats, you know, yeah.
That's the way the world works.
Every country has unelected bureaucrats.
That's how governments operate.
Who elected the Nuremberg Tribunal?
Nobody. They were appointed by the
United States, Britain, France, and the
Soviet Union.
And it worked. It showed that rule of
law is really a thing that needs to be
respected.
I've said multiple times in multiple
venues, you cannot have your policy
be to just go into some place like Gaza
or the West Bank and kill everybody.
Men, women, children, the elderly. You
flatten the hospitals, you flatten the
flatten the homes, you flatten the
schools, and then whoever survives, you
starve them.
Those are war crimes and crimes against
humanity.
And sure, the United States, which I
believe strongly, is wrong on this
issue. The United States is going to
save you.
But most other countries aren't.
They aren't going to save you.
Yesterday,
we got another bombshell. This is
Netanyahu strategizing with Lindsey
Graham about how to discredit the ICC
when they came out with their ruling
that Netanyahu had likely committed war
crimes. Listen to this. It's Lindsey
Graham on the phone with Netanyahu.
>> [clears throat]
>> I I tell you the perfect person would be
the speaker, Speaker Johnson.
>> [clears throat]
>> Speaker Johnson.
No, to have to have him on the letter.
I don't know. I won't know doubt try.
But I will try. I promise you that.
>> So let's let's unpack that.
Did you catch how casual their tone was?
Uh let me brainstorm some Democrats we
can get to cosign. And of course there
will be or there would have been
Democrats Natanyahu there is talking
exactly like how he would say say call a
friend if a judge were to find him
guilty of a crime. No plan
desperate for anything.
I'm going to call my friend Lindsey.
See if Lindsey can write a strongly
worded letter.
Get a bunch of important people to sign
it.
And um
hope for the best. What else are you
going to do? Let me read for you the
rest of that reporting from the New York
Times because it's it's shocking. You're
going to want to hear it.
Quote
Mr. Holder recorded the audio without
video of a second call between the two
men that he said took place later that
day. Only Mr. Graham's voice could be
heard.
On that call Mr. Graham joked to Mr.
Netanyahu who that he should quote pay
me for all this. I should get tons of
shekels. Unquote.
It would take quote more than dinner.
Unquote. He added. Then he said that
quote we got them both. Unquote.
Appearing to refer to Senators Richard
Blumenthal of Connecticut
and Ben Cardin of Maryland two Democrats
who said they would sign a letter
protesting the efforts to move ahead
with an arrest warrant.
Quote, "So, here's why I'm calling you."
Mr. Graham told Mr. Netanyahu saying
that he hoped to get the letter, quote,
"out the door Wednesday."
Unquote, appearing to refer to the next
day, October 30th. Quote, "So, send me
over whatever you want to say."
"And they want to say two things to the
ICC." Unquote. One was that the
prosecutor should speak with the Israeli
government and not move ahead with the
case until, quote, "the cloud is
lifted." Unquote, from the prosecutor's
own problems.
What Mr. Graham requested in exchange,
he said, was for Mr. Netanyahu, quote,
"to call Blumenthal and Cardin and thank
them for being fair-minded on this and
also thank them for trying to help with
Saudi-Israel normalization."
"You appreciate it. You're very
interested in it and that will encourage
both of them." Unquote.
The letter was released on November 1st,
2024.
And it included Mr. Blumenthal and Mr.
Cardin as signers. In addition to noting
the allegations against Mr. Khan, the
prosecutor,
who just resigned a week ago because of
sexual improprieties.
The letter said that the ICC,
quote, "did not comply." Unquote, with
the law
by declining to keep a planned meeting
with Israeli representatives before
applying for the arrest warrant. None of
them responded for comment.
Um,
I'm very sensitive
to
the term espionage.
Um, I mentioned in a previous episode
that in my case, my judge set a new
legal precedent for application of the
Espionage Act.
And she determined that espionage was
very simply
providing national defense information
to any person not entitled to receive
it.
Simple.
None of these documentary filmmakers
were cleared for classified information,
and literally everything that Lindsey
Graham is talking about is classified.
People in the United States have gone to
prison for far less collusion with a
foreign leader than what he we have seen
in these tapes, these videos
of Lindsey Graham and Benjamin
Netanyahu.
And it also leads me to ask
where in the world America's
relationship with Israel is headed.
Where will it be in 5, 10, 30 years?
I mentioned in the last five there's
been a 50 percentage point split or move
away
from support for Israel.
And now the vast majority of Democrats,
the vast majority of independents,
and a sizeable
number of Republicans
think that Benjamin Netanyahu committed
war crimes and that he should be
prosecuted. Have you ever wondered what
it feels like to shoot with the same
precision tech used by US special
forces? Well, good news. After years of
research and development, MCG Tactical
just dropped something incredible, the
Stinger Combat Sight. This is not your
average red dot. Using holographic
technology once reserved for elite
military and law enforcement, the
Stinger delivers crystal-clear
precision. So accurate that you could
hit a dime at 300 yd without even
trying.
This is the exact same level of
technology used by the pros, but here's
the twist. Most sights like this go for
600 bucks or more, and people happily
pay it. But right now, through an
exclusive deal with MCG Tactical, you
can get this mil-spec site for under
$200.
And it gets better. For my listeners,
you're getting 67% off, and they're
covering shipping.
You know, I talk all the time about not
yet having my gun rights back. It's
something that my attorneys and I are
working on. But I am still a regular at
gun shows in the Washington DC area. And
I can tell you that there are different
sites out there. There are different
lasers and red dots that you can look
at. Nothing Nothing is as good as this.
So, just scan the QR code or go to
mcgtac.com/johnsting
to get yours today. The only catch,
supply is tight, and these are already
flying off the shelves. So, if you want
a site built for the best, now's your
chance. Grab yours before they have to
shut down orders. That is
mcgtac.com/johnsting.
Well, welcome to a new segment that
we're going to call the profile.
When I was in the CIA, it used to be my
job. It was my very first job in the CIA
to
to profile foreign leaders for the
president, the vice president, the
national security advisor, and the
secretaries of state and defense.
Anytime they were seeing a world leader,
we had to write a classified
psychological profile of that world
leader.
And I still kind of enjoyed doing it
just for myself.
My job at the agency when I first got
hired was uh to be essentially
Saddam Hussein's classified biographer
for the intelligence community. His
His
classified
psychological biographer. And I worked
with a team of psychiatrists,
psychologists, and anthropologists to
make sure that that we had cutting-edge
analysis.
Well, our first profile is going to be
on a man named Reza Pahlavi.
Someone who also attended Lindsey
Graham's funeral yesterday in
Washington. Reza Pahlavi is the former
Crown Prince and the eldest son of the
last Shah of Iran.
He's been waiting in the wings,
attempting to jockey to lead Iran in the
event of regime change.
You're going to hear how charismatic he
is in these clips. And you can make your
own decision as to how likely it is that
he's going to be the leader of Iran. But
let me say a couple of things about Reza
Pahlavi.
Um I not so jokingly have referred to
him in podcast appearances in the past
as the Clown Prince of Iran.
He left Iran as a very young man,
in his very early 20s, or about the age
of 20, in 1979.
He hasn't been back to Iran since 1979.
He is strongly supported
by Israel,
uh by the Jewish community here in
America,
by the Iranian exile community here in
America. Not the entire community, but I
mean like the Southern California very
wealthy uh Iranian exiles.
He lives in a multi-million dollar
palace in Potomac, Maryland, a close-in
suburb of Washington, D.C.
But he's not a player.
He's never been a player.
Since the US and Israel began bombing
Iran, he's appeared on a handful of
podcasts. He was on the Patrick
Bet-David Show
uh once or twice, and a couple of other
podcasts,
in which he sort of says what you would
expect him to say that, you know, yes,
the regime is terrible, it has to be
overthrown, the Iranian people have to
be liberated. And then sometimes he'll
say that he's the one who should lead
Iran, and other times he says that he's
not the one who should lead Iran. The
truth is
he would and I've I've said this in the
past and I've gotten death threats for
it. I'm going to say it again. He would
not survive the walk from the plane to
the terminal if he were to go back to
Iran.
Nobody wants him
in Iran. Nobody.
And if there's one thing that the
Israeli and American bombing of Iran
has done
is that it's united the Iranian people.
You can't
you can't attack a country
murder its religious leader
murder most of its senior governmental
leadership
murder all of its military leaders
murder all of its nuclear scientists and
say, "We're here to help."
We know we've been bombing you and we
the first night of the bombing we blew
up the school and killed 160-something
little girls from the school, but but
we're the good guys and we're here to
help you and we want to take this stooge
this clown from Potomac, Maryland and
impose him on you so that he can be a
dictator like his father was.
Well, the reason that that Reza
Pahlavi's father
Mohammad Reza Pahlavi was overthrown in
the first place is because he was a
bloodthirsty murderous dictator.
And people were tired
of being murdered
by the SAVAK, the secret police.
So, Reza Pahlavi's not going back to
Iran. He's not going to lead Iran. He's
not going to be a player in any
respect.
Although
the pro-war faction of the Republican
Party
and the Israeli government think he's
great.
We've got a little clip that we want to
show you of an interview that Reza
Pahlavi did yesterday with Reuters.
>> There have been reports, uh, they're
kind of anonymous, that you've received
funding from Israel and Saudi Arabia. Is
that true?
>> Absolutely false. I have not been a
recipient of any governmental or public
fund on the outside.
Every dime that comes to my campaign
comes from private donations uh of
supporters. Hopefully, we'll have more
benefactors that'll give us bigger
checks.
>> From where we're sitting today, when do
you think regime change might occur?
>> I think we're very close to it. And the
reason I say this is because, first and
foremost, the regime is at its weakest
it's ever been since 47 years.
Not to mention the fact that in terms of
legitimacy, it has totally lost any
remaining possible legitimacy it might
have had.
>> It's just wrong.
He's just wrong.
He forgets that when his father was
first overthrown, Iran went through a
series of presidents. There was even an
editorial cartoon at the time, I
remember, in the New York Times, where
Ayatollah Khomeini was telling some
Iranian-looking guy, "I have good news
and I have bad news. The good news is,
I'm naming you president of Iran. The
bad news is, I'm naming you president of
Iran.
Because there was a cycle of presidents
of Iran that would just get blown up or
shot or arrested or disappeared or
whatever.
That was when the regime was weak.
Not today.
This war has forced
the Iranian populace together. To rally.
You know, you would think that we would
have learned a lesson
with the Iraq war.
We have so convinced ourselves that
we're the good guys. We just can't
fathom the notion that when we cross a
border, we're not going to be seen as
liberators. We're going to be seen as
invaders and occupiers. It happens time
and time again. We couldn't defeat the
Taliban. They didn't even have shoes.
And they beat us.
We couldn't defeat the Iraqis. Iraq is
still in a state of chaos.
But we think that we're going to be
greeted in as liberators in Iran?
Why would we think that?
We would think that because people don't
have any understanding of history.
So here is this clown waiting in the
wings pretending to jockey to lead Iran
in the event of regime change.
Well, I would liken him to Ahmed
Chalabi.
For those of you who don't remember
Ahmed Chalabi, he was a similar clown
that was in the pay of the CIA, the
American government. And we made this
really stupid plan to make him the
president of Iraq as soon as we
overthrew Saddam Hussein. And the Iraqi
people said, "Oh, no, you don't."
Well, it's happening again.
Finally, one of the things that the
Iranian government has been really good
at since the start of this war is
propaganda.
I enjoy looking at pieces of propaganda
because some of them are really great
and some of them are really terrible.
I've told the story a couple of times
about my last visit to Yemen in 2011. I
met with the US defense attache in the
American Embassy in Sana'a.
And I asked him kind of offhandedly,
"So, what are you working on? What's
new?" And he said, "Oh, we've got this
wonderful psyop, psychological
operation. It's a propaganda operation."
I said, "Oh, cool. What are you doing?"
And he said,
"We've created a pirate radio station
and we're broadcasting jazz
across Yemen. And then at the end of
each hour, you can call in
and talk about the jazz."
I said, "Why would you do that?"
"Well,
it's going to make people like jazz.
And they know that jazz is American, and
so that'll make them like America."
How'd that work out for us?
Jazz
in Yemen.
There's not enough food.
People are literally starving to death.
They're constantly at war, if not with
each other, with Saudi Arabia and now
with everybody else.
But they're going to listen to jazz and
call the propaganda station to talk
about how great the jazz is.
Well, the Iranians are not making jazz
stations. They're making Lego
animations. And these Lego animations
are fantastic. Let's take a look at the
latest one.
>> Hey, hey, hey, Chad, old man.
Your empire is done.
You You [music] the war. You thought you
would win.
>> Uh-huh.
>> Now look at the mess that your country
is in. Look at it. Your generals crying
your plan was a bust. The promises made
are turning to dust. Marco Rubio was
sweating [music] these grovel on the
floor. They [singing] asked for the
billions you wasted on war. You laughed
from day one. You kept capping a lot.
But look at the straight you we got it
on lock. Lock down. Begging for mercy
you're begging for [music] peace while
telling your media Iran wants peace. You
sure?
You're losing the straight.
>> [music]
>> You're losing the state. And now the
whole public is drowning in You told
stop talking about Epstein. Now listen
to the crowd.
Louder.
>> [music]
>> No, stop talking about
Louder.
>> [music]
>> You lied about Iran.
>> That is very sophisticated.
The purpose of it is not to convince
Americans
to switch sides and you know, side with
Iran. Although that would be a benefit
that the Iranian regime I think would
would appreciate.
It's to influence everybody else in
between.
European public opinion. Really broader
world public opinion.
Um the Iranians have produced at least a
half a dozen of these and each one is
more creative than than the previous
one.
Now compare that to some of the
propaganda that we see from other
countries. Not the American stupid jazz
idea. But let's say from the Russians.
You know, the Democrats were adamant
that the Russians tried to steal the
2016 election for Donald Trump. That
turned out to be untrue. And in fact,
the Russian government spent $50,000 on
Facebook advertising. But 25,000 of the
50,000 was spent after the election was
over. And the remaining 25,000 was spent
in states that were already either
solidly blue or solidly red.
And what was that propaganda?
It was
pictures of kittens and puppies and
flowers and then the occasional mention
of, you know, politics.
Big deal. It was a failure. The Chinese
are no better and it's because the
Chinese don't really understand American
culture and we don't really feel a
connection to Chinese culture because
most of us are, you know, of European
origin or South American, Latin American
origin or African origin, not East Asian
origin. And so the the thought process
is different when it comes to
propaganda. But this from the Iranians
is very sophisticated.
And they're going to keep coming out
with more of them in order to influence
college students, let's say, or working
people,
mostly in Europe.
And to get them to separate themselves
from the US and Israel. It's something
that really bears watching.
Folks, I wanted to thank you again for
your embrace of this
this podcast. I have to say I'm I'm
speechless when I I look at the numbers
each day.
I make a joke when I do cameos that
if it wasn't for you and people like
you, I would be living in the backseat
of my car at the Walmart parking lot
over in Fairfax, Virginia.
But that's only kind of a half a joke
for me. Like my sister, God bless her.
My sister's my best friend and my sister
always says, "No, you would live with
me." And I'm like, "Yeah, I'm I'd be an
old man living in my sister's basement."
But in all seriousness, it's only
because of you
that we're able to do this and that
we're able to keep it going as an
ongoing concern. So, thank you for
watching. Thank you for your emails and
your questions. Thank you for liking and
sharing and subscribing.
It really means the world to us and
we're going to keep it going because you
like it and we like doing it. So, thank
you. I'm John Kiriakou. This is The
Briefing Room and we'll see you again
next time.